{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of these restriction enzymes produce blunt ends?", "opta": "SaII", "optb": "EcoRV", "optc": "XhoI", "optd": "HindIII", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The RP13 gene of chromosome 17 codes for a protein __________ .", "opta": "involved in glucose transport", "optb": "that is a component of hair and nails", "optc": "involved in eye development", "optd": "involved in the determination of personality", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Isoschizomers recognize", "opta": "same recognition sequence but different recognition site", "optb": "same recognition site and recognition sequence", "optc": "same recognition site and different recognition sequence", "optd": "different recognition site and different recognition sequence", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Restriction enzymes are named for", "opta": "the person who discovered", "optb": "the bacterium they are derived from", "optc": "the viral DNA that they attack", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of these genes codes for a protein that plays a role in white blood cell function?", "opta": "DCP1", "optb": "MPO", "optc": "GLUT4", "optd": "RP13", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When populations are small, gene frequencies can change from generation to generation and some alleles may become fixed in a population. This is called __________ .", "opta": "assortative mating", "optb": "inbreeding", "optc": "heterosis", "optd": "genetic drift", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct in terms of determination of location of genetic traits?", "opta": "Known protein coding sequences are too far apart to allow linkage determination for most new genes", "optb": "Restriction sites allow DNAs to be digested", "optc": "Protein-coding genes are always associated with a restriction pattern", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In gel electrophoresis, DNA molecules migrate from __________ to __________ ends of the gel.", "opta": "negative ... positive", "optb": "basic ... acidic", "optc": "long ... short", "optd": "positive to negative", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Restriction enzymes", "opta": "protect bacteria from viral infection", "optb": "cut DNA in a staggered fashion", "optc": "cut DNAs producing a blunt end", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "First discovered, Type II restriction endonuclease was", "opta": "Hinf I", "optb": "Eco K", "optc": "Hind II", "optd": "EcoRI", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following techniques can be used to determine the defective gene and for developing cancer?", "opta": "Western blot", "optb": "Southern blot", "optc": "Northern blot", "optd": "Eastern blot", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The transfer of antibiotic-resistant genes from genetically engineered bacteria to disease-causing bacteria __________ .", "opta": "would be of no concern if it occurred.", "optb": "has occurred", "optc": "can never occur", "optd": "seems unlikely", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Both DNA gel electrophoresis and SDS-PAGE of proteins are similar because", "opta": "in both cases molecules migrate to the anode", "optb": "both techniques rely on a constant charge to mass ratio", "optc": "both techniques utilize the sieving properties of gels", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Some genetic diseases cannot be diagnosed by changes in restriction sites. Some of these can be detected by allele-specific oligonucleotide probes. These are", "opta": "copies of the gene with an altered sequence so that a restriction site is inserted", "optb": "mutagenized copies of a gene", "optc": "short sequences that will hybridize only to a specific base sequence", "optd": "PCR-amplified variable numbers of tandem repeats (VNTRs)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In order to insert a foreign gene into a plasmid, both must __________", "opta": "have identical DNA sequences", "optb": "originate from the same type of cell", "optc": "be cut by the same restriction enzyme", "optd": "be of the same length", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following genetic diseases would be amenable to genetic engineering?", "opta": "Down's syndrome", "optb": "Muscular dystrophy", "optc": "Cystic fibrosis", "optd": "Cri du Chat", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "X-rays cause", "opta": "the formation of thymine dimers", "optb": "ionization of water in the cell", "optc": "heat", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The order for the construction of a cDNA fragment from mRNA is to", "opta": "bind oligo-dT, treat with reverse transcriptase, digest with RNase, add G residues to the 3' end, bind oligo-dC, treat with DNA polymerase", "optb": "treat with reverse transcriptase, digest with RNase, add G residues to the 3' end, bind oligo-dC, treat with DNA polymerase and bind oligo-dT", "optc": "digest with RNase, add G residues to the 3' end, treat with reverse transcriptase, add G residues to the 3' end and treat with DNA polymerase", "optd": "bind oligo-dC, treat with reverse transcriptase, digest with RNase, add G residues to the 3' end, bind oligo-dT and treat with DNA polymerase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The TP53 gene of chromosome 17 codes for a protein __________ .", "opta": "that plays a role in the digestive process", "optb": "involved in glucose transport", "optc": "involved in the regulation of the cell cycle", "optd": "that is like a white blood cell protein", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why is golden rice pale yellow in color?", "opta": "It is rich in chlorophyll a.", "optb": "It is rich in beta-carotene.", "optc": "It is rich in chlorophyll b.", "optd": "It is rich in phycobilins.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of restriction enzymes do not usually require ATP?", "opta": "Type I", "optb": "Type II", "optc": "Type III", "optd": "Type IV", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An example of a restriction fragment length polymorphism is", "opta": "an Eco RI cuts DNA at a different sequence than Hind III", "optb": "different length fragments of DNA resulting from loss or gain of a restriction site", "optc": "cystic fibrosis results from a three base deletion in most cases but in other cases, other mutations are involved", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Knockout mice are created by", "opta": "mutagenizing a mouse and selecting for mutant offspring", "optb": "creating a chimera by fusing cells from two different cell lines", "optc": "infecting the mouse with a retrovirus", "optd": "transfecting embryonic stem cells with an altered gene sequence", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A plasmid", "opta": "is a circular DNA molecule", "optb": "always contains an origin of replication", "optc": "usually contains one or more restriction sites", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Under which of the following conditions would population gene frequencies remain the same?", "opta": "Selection for homozygotes", "optb": "Small population size", "optc": "Active migration between groups", "optd": "Random mating", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Plant transformation can be obtained by", "opta": "combining plant and animal cells in culture", "optb": "shooting DNA into plant cells with a gun", "optc": "using the E. coli bacterium to infect plant roots", "optd": "infecting plants with a tobacco mosaic virus", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An expression vector", "opta": "always contains an origin of replication", "optb": "usually contains a gene that confers antibiotic resistance to the bacterial host", "optc": "always contains DNA segments for the regulation of mRNA production", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The unpaired nucleotides produced by the action of restriction enzymes are referred to have", "opta": "sticky ends", "optb": "single strands", "optc": "restriction fragments", "optd": "ligases", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not true of small inbreeding populations?", "opta": "They tend to loose genetic diversity", "optb": "There is an increased incidence of recessive diseases", "optc": "Alleles may become fixed", "optd": "Mutation is increased", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of these genes codes for a protein that plays a role in growth?", "opta": "DCP1", "optb": "SCLC6A4", "optc": "KRTHA1", "optd": "GH1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following pair will produce complementary sticky ends?", "opta": "Eco RI & MspI", "optb": "Msp I & HPA II", "optc": "Sau 3A & Bam HI", "optd": "Mbo I & Sau 3A", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A human cDNA library", "opta": "contains DNA for specific human proteins", "optb": "contains DNA for virtually all of the human proteins in vectors", "optc": "cannot be used to obtain human genes because it would be radioactive", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What enzyme forms covalent bonds between restriction fragments?", "opta": "DNA primase", "optb": "DNA helicase", "optc": "DNA polymerase", "optd": "DNA ligase", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following can be diagnosed by amniocentesis?", "opta": "Down's syndrome", "optb": "Cystic Fibrosis", "optc": "Sickle cell anemia", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}